If you want to send your friend a message that
is impossible for anyone else to read, do this.
Start by making a truly random digit code.
You could use dice and a table like this one.
This code is the key you can only use once.
You and your friend should memorize or safely store this.
When you want to send a message to your
friend, first turn your message into a digit code.
You could use a straddling checkerboard to do this.
Then subtract each digit in your key from a
digit in the same position from your message.
If the key digit is more than the
message digit, add ten to the message digit.
Then send the digits you get from the subtractions to your friend.
If you receive a message like this from your friend, add back each
digit from the key into what they sent. Do not carry between digits.
Then you can turn the digit code back into a message you can read.
Make sure the key is longer than or
equal to the code from the message.
Then the message will be just as secret as the key.